

CONTACT



11, Redemption Close, Adams Estate, Ikotun, Lagos 234



+2348167590644



bamoyk@yahoo.com



https://youtube.com/c/delaroystud



https://www.linkedin.com/in/bamidele-oguntuga-8779

SKILLS

- Kotlin
- Android
- Java
- IOS
- REST API integration
- Swift
- Unit testing
- Git

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Bamidele Oguntuga
- +2348167590644

Bamidele Oguntuga

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate and highly effective developer who has successfully developed applications for Android and iOS. Well-educated and poised with more than 8 years of expertise. Seeking an exciting opportunity to create and test mobile apps for a company in the education, finance, logistics, media, hospitality, travel sector, etc.

WORK HISTORY

Android Engineer TouchandPay Technologies - Lagos

05/2021 - Current

- Design and develop all Android payment technologies, POS, apps etc
- Integrate various payment gateways and methods (credit card, NFC, QR code, etc.) into the POS application.
- Applied various techniques to locate bugs in applications in an efficient manner.
- Provided weekly progress report to executive staff, ensuring that all parties were informed of milestones.
- Provided dedicated support and timely issue resolution to clients following successful app launch.
- Involved in all aspects of Android app life cycle from research and planning to deployment and post-launch support.
- Tested applications prior to final review to ensure that all issues were resolved in the most efficient manner.

Android and iOS Developer

04/2020 - 04/2021

Evertus Pte Ltd - 6001 Beach Rd, Singapore

- Design and develop SkillBox Android and iOS mobile application.
- Integrate all Web ServiceAPI's for Android development.
- Establish database schemas and logics involved in backend development.
- Deploying of SkillBox mobile app to stores.
- Continual maintenance and support to all Evertus mobile products
- Translated complex developer issues to large audiences.

Lead Android Developer

04/2019 - 01/2020

LokDon LLC - Minnesota, South Carolina, USA

- Design, develop Lokdon Android mobile application
- Integrate all Web Service APIs for Android development.
- Continuous integration and maintenance Deploying of Lokdon mobile app to stores

Android and iOS Developer

12/2018 - 12/2019

2Toc Solutions Limited - Airport Road, Abuja

- Design and develop NISPSAS (Nigerian Security Alert System) Android platform.
- Design and develop NISPSAS iOS platform.
- Work closely with backend developers to integrate API logics to app

Android and iOS Developer Comsoft Limited - Garki, FCT, Abuja

- Working with server-sideAPI's.
- Consuming complex APIs for development of CAFMS.
- Design and Develop CAFMS mobile app for Android and iOS which is complete accounting and book keeping record app for businesses and individuals

Android Software Developer

02/2018 - 08/2018

Flexisaf Edusoft Limited - Garki, FCT, Abuja

- Translate designs and wireframes into high quality code.
- Work with external data sources and APIs.
- Design and develop SRMS Android mobile app which is complete and robust tertiary institution management system

Android and Web Software Developer

08/2015 - 01/2018

Delaroy Studios - Lagos

- Acting as lead Android developer
- Deliver across entire app life cycle -concept, design, build, deploy, test, release to app stores.
- Gather requirements around functionality and translate those requirements into elegant functional solutions.
- Anchoring Delaroy Studios YouTube Channel which basically focus on Android development
- Development Tutorials

Website and Mobile Software Developer

09/2014 - 05/2015

eKnowvateSolutions Limited - Lagos

- Create website layout/user interface by using standard HTML/CSS practices.
- Integrate data from various back-end web services and databases.
- Gather and refine specifications and requirements based on technical needs
- Create and maintain software documentation.
- Be responsible for maintaining, expanding, and scaling client websites

Administrative Officer

10/2012 - 07/2014

The Law Offices of Dr Wunmi Bewaji & Co - Lagos

- Manage office supplies stock and place orders.
- Maintain and update company databases.
- Develop proper filing system for important and confidential company documents.
- · Answer queries by employees and clients.
- Update office policies as needed

Website Developer

04/2011 - 03/2012

Oasis Solutions Limited - Lagos

- Design, develop, test, and maintain web-based applications built on various web technologies
- Assisting in collection and documentation of user's requirements, development of user stories, and estimates
- Interacting with project stakeholders to develop storyboards and UX workflows/prototypes

- Providing stylization and theming customization
- Ensuring cross-browser compatibility across variety of supported browsers

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Business Administration and Computer **Olabisi Onabanjo University** - Ago Iwoye, Nigeria

Oracle Certified Professional (Oracle Database11g): Oracle Database
Oracle Corporation - Redwood California, United States

Associate Android Developer: Android, 03/2017

Google Inc - Mountain View California

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Good communication skills
- Organisational/ managerial skills
- Acquired good managerial skills as an Administrative Officer, two years in a renowned law practice firm has spurn my managerial abilities coupled with business management as well
- Google Certified AssociateAndroid Developer, https://bcert.me/bc/html/show-badge.html?b=chodqgz.
- Oracle Certified Professional (Oracle Database11g).
- Associate Nigeria Institute of Management.
- Delaroy Studios, Android development YouTube Channel over 4 million views over 20 thousand subscribers, https://youtube.com/c/delaroystudios.
- Android On to One Chatting App in Firebase: https://youtu.be/2tRavgYG4ks
- Android Recylerview and Card Layout: https://youtu.be/A2_6ml7drVQ
- QRBarcode Scanner ordinary and smart You can DECODE text, urls,ISBN, email, contacts information, calendar events and much more with a single click using your smartphone camera, image files, online codes. Develop the mobile application
 - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=appinventor.ai_progetto2003.SCAN
- CISSP Risk Assessment Score by Impact and Threat Analysis (RASBITA) is an
 application to help the government and enterprise agencies obtain the risk
 score for all IT security incidents. I develop the mobile application
 https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rasbitasecurity
- CAFMS, Cabsol Accounting and Financial Management A complete and robust accounting and financial management system for individuals, smalland large-scale businesses, corporations and not for profit making businesses. I develop the Android mobile application https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.cafms.cafmsmobile&hl =en
- Nigeria Internal Security and Public Safety Alert System (NISPSAS) is part of Federal Government efforts to provide adequate and prompt response to emergency and safety of lives and properties. Mobile Application dashboard for the public to report Fire, Crime, Medical and Accident distresses. I develop the mobile application https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.a2tocsolutions.nispsas app
- Alpha Shop The Alpha App provides the best transaction experience between buyers and sellers, bridging the gap between e-commerce and social-media. I develop the Android mobile application from the beginning

to the end all alone $\underline{\text{https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.thealphashops@hl=en}}$ &gl=US